Ahmed Saber Fathy

Desouk, Kafr El Sheikh, Egypt (GMT+2)

J +20 120 861 1892

■ ahmed0saber33@gmail.com

• https://github.com/ahmed0saber

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed0saber/

Summary

Hello there, My name is Ahmed Saber, I'm a React.js Frontend Web Developer who has 2+ years of team work experience and open source contributions, and 1+ years of work experience in the industry of frontend web development, I enjoy building everything with JavaScript.

In this duration, I have learned a lot of technologies, created many cool websites, collaborated with great developers and contributed to open source projects. So I'm always seeking to have an opportunity that matches my skills, to make the best use of all what I have learned.

Skills

> HTML5

> JavaScript (ES6)

> jQuery

> SASS

> Redux & Redux toolkit

> Electron.js

> CSS3

> JSON

> Bootstrap

> React.js

> Next.js

> Socket.io

Languages

> Arabic - native

> English - conversational

Experience

> Frontend Web Developer - Full Time

Valinteca - Remote April 2022 - Present

> Frontend Web Developer - Virtual Internship

LetsGrowMore - Remote September 2022 - October 2022

> React JS Developer - Internship

Across The Globe (ATG) - Remote

April 2022 - May 2022

Education

> Bachelor of Science - Physics Department
Kafr El Sheikh university - Kafr El Sheikh - Egypt
Undergraduate, 2019 - 2023

Projects

> My Portfolio

That's my personal website where I show my skills and projects.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSON, React.js
- View at https://ahmed0saber.onrender.com

> XO Online

XO game where you can play vs easy or hard bot, vs local or online player, chat with people, invite them, win more games and rank up.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Socket.io
- View at https://xo-online.herokuapp.com

> TestMode

A website where you can test your skills in some technologies related to programming and get certified.

- Built with HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, JSON, React.js, Next.js
- View at https://testmode.vercel.app

Community Activities

> Frontend Web JavaScript Instructor

Az-SENCS, March 2022 - June 2022

> Frontend Web Development Trainee

MSP Al Azhar university, February 2022 - March 2022

> Frontend Web Development Trainee

GDSC Assuit university, November 2021 - December 2021

Certificates

- > FreeCodeCamp certified Frontend Web Developer
- Verify at

https://github.com/ahmed0saber/certifications/tree/main/Freecodecamp

- > EgFWD certified Web Designer
- Verify at https://github.com/ahmed0saber/certifications/blob/main/egfwd-challenger.pdf
- > MaharaTech certified Frontend Web Developer
- Verify at https://github.com/ahmed0saber/certifications/